FATHIN DOSUNMU

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+37253653094 Tallinn, Estonia

Fathindos.fd@gmail.com https://fathin.vercel.app/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/fathindos/ https://medium.com/@fathindos.fd https://tryhackme.com/p/Candidate14

Software engineer with over 4 years of experience in frontend and backend development. skills in React JS, Next JS, firebase, Node JS, Typescript and Web Security. Experience designing and developing websites from concept to roll out and Passionate about cyber security. Even though I love to get my work done in the best way, I am a lifelong learner and I like to think I have a great sense of humour.

EDUCATION

Master of Science: Cyber Security

Taltech - Tallinn, Estonia, 2020 -2023

Https://www.taltech.ee/en/cyber-msc

Development Skills

- Firebase
- Google Cloud API
- React is
- Javascript
- REST APIs
- Microsoft Power BI
 Chakra UI
- Graph API
- Problem solving
- Node js
- Typescript
- Next is
- Graphql
- Upstash Redis

 - PlanetScale
 - Prisma

Bachelor of Science: Integrated Engineering

Taltech - Tallinn, Estonia, 2017-2020

Https://www.taltech.ee/en/integrated-engineering.

- SASS
- styled components
- vercel
- mixpanel
- Vercel
- Material UI
- Semantic UI
- Shadcn UI
- PlanetScale DB

- Clerk Auth
- Node is
- Jest
- Cypress
- Lighthouse
- Contentful
- Git
- Jenkins
- ArgoCI/ArgoCD

CyberSecurity Skills

- Burp Suite -Repeater, intruder
- Owasp Zap
- Kali-linux
- Wireshark
- OWSASP top 10
- Checkmarx

- Malware analysis
- Metasploit
- TryHackMe CTFs and Rooms

WORK EXPERIENCE

Zing

Senior Frontend Software Developer. Tallinn. 2022-10 - Present

- Developed website products from concept to roll out with React JS, typescript
- Founding developer for the marketing website
- Helped estimate delivery time on the technical implementation of new product features
- Helped with knowledge transfer to the new devs joining the team.
- Documented and thought out processes for new developers joining the team
- Architected the structure of interaction of custom Next API routes with 3rd party API routes and BE API routes
- Suggested improvements in the codebase to have always reusable components and make use of story book for documenting components
- Conducted Static Application Security Testing (SAST) using Checkmarx to identify and remediate code vulnerabilities.
- Implemented security best practices based on OWASP top 10, including input validation, authentication, and authorization mechanisms in API.
- Fixed Website accessibility violations
- Wrote unit tests, end-end tests, about 75% coverage for the used components marketing web
- Developed an API health check API endpoint to validate the health status of the website at all times
- Debugged Root cause and Fixed Incidents that happened in production

Monese

Frontend Software Developer. Tallinn. 2022-10 - 2024-01

- Developed website products from concept to roll out with React JS, ts
- rendered content dynamically with our contentful CMS content delivery API
- Refactored and updated components to follow modern UI standards based on Figma designs provided by our in-house designers
- Found, Reported and Fixed bugs caught on the product website
- Remediated vulnerabilities from security code scanners to eliminate high-critical vulnerabilities
- Developed API and Architected custom Next API routes which served as a proxy to other 3rd party API services such as mixpanel and viral loops
- Revised, Modullarised and updated legacy code to modern development standards
- Improved the lighthouse performance score from a low of 73 to 93
- Integrated bitbucket pipelines in the code base to automate linting, test validation and project build
- Collaborated with other developers and other tribes to create new features
- and more...

Exove

Developer, Tallinn. 2021-09 - 2022-10

- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Creating new features for clients with React is, node is, redux, firebase and more
- Checked client code for bugs and weaknesses and reported them
- Implemented PowerBI reports with Microsoft PowerBI API for reporting sales survey for its client

Kuehne+nagel

Frontend Developer Intern, Tallinn. 2021-06 - 2021-08

- Developed in house Saas with react, redux for state management
- Collaborated with other interns to achieve goals set by our ment

The Fundamental Secret

Full-stack developer, Remote. 2020-08 - 2021-05

- Responsible for developing website products used by approximately 600 + users
- Planned website development, converting ideas into features with HTML, JavaScript, React-js and Firebase
- Implemented payment gateways with PayPal and Stripe.
- Oversaw front-end with mainly React-js and back-end development with mainly Firebase.
- lots of code breaking and fixing

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Recently started working on a universal web Scraper leveraging the power of AI agents: https://github.com/Fato07/Universal-Scraper.git
- Live Widget Editor: https://viral-loops-form-widget-editor.vercel.app/
 Please check the readme file for a detailed idea of the project setup and tech stack
- Personal Blog post, where I write about cyber security, hacking and the interesting machine I have hacked on tryhackme: <u>https://medium.com/@fathindos.fd</u>
- Personal Website to showcase my skillset: https://fathin.vercel.app/ (React js, GitHub API, vercel for deployments)
- Built a clone of whatsApp Chat. A User can signIn, Post a chat in a chat room and chat with other users: https://whatsapp-clone-bd456.web.app/ (React js and Firebase for development)
- I love playing CTFS on tryHack me. where i learn a lot about cyber security and compete with other hackers: https://tryhackme.com/p/Candidate14
- Lots of hackathons as well...